All those years, all those dreams, all those sons...
one of them is going to be a star.
American Pop is a animation, music, drama film directed by Ralph Bakshi.
The history of American popular music runs parallel with the history of a Russian Jewish
immigrant family, with each male descendant possessing different musical abilities.
Tony Belinksy / Pete Belinksy (voice), played by Ron Thompson.
Bella (voice), played by Lisa Jane Persky.
Zalmie Belinksy (voice), played by Jeffrey Lippa.
Crisco (voice), played by Frank De Kova.
Eva Tanguay (voice), played by Roz Kelly.
Frankie (as Marya Small), played by Mews Small.
American Pop is a 1981 American adult animated epic jukebox musical drama film
starring Ron Thompson and produced and directed by Ralph Bakshi.
It was the fourth animated feature film to be presented in Dolby sound.
The film tells the story of four generations of the Belinskys, an immigrant family of musicians
whose careers parallel the history of American popular music in the 20th century.
The majority of the film's animation was completed through rotoscoping, a process in which live
actors are filmed and the subsequent footage is used for animators to draw over.
However, the film also uses a variety of other media including
water-colors, live-action shots, and archival footage.
The film explores themes of jazz, pop, czar / tsar
/ tzar, mafia boss, folk music.
The tone is emotional.